美丽的早上,有什么可为您服务的?
Com how can I help youthis beautiful morning?
你有病人么?
You got any cases?
三个
Three.
黑人少女需要肺移植
I got a teenage,african-americanlung transplant
以后几天你除了门诊什么都不要做
next few days you'll be doing nothing but clinic work.
- 我刚刚说,- 你在撒谎!
- I just said- - you're lying!
那干嘛还问?
Then why'd you ask?
如果你刚刚说真话,我就只给你一天门诊任务
Because if you told the truth,I was only gonna give youone day of clinic duty.
真奸诈
That's dishonest.
- 我拒绝接受...,- 你会去做的
- I refuse to participate in this - you'll do it.
你欠我的 我把你从监狱救出来
You owe me.I kept you out of jail.
也能让你回去
I can put you back.
做伪证的
Perjurer.
犯人
Felon.
美丽的早上,有什么可为您服务的?
How can I help youthis beautiful morning?
我跟护士说我流鼻涕 但是我没
I told the nurseI have a runny nose,but I don'T.
我 我想我有...
I-I think I have,uh.
梅毒或者淋病
syphilis or gonorrhea.
我觉得我得了性病
I think I have an std.
我觉得我得了...
I think I have A.
这有谁流鼻涕
who is herefor a runny nose?
那是伤风
It's a cold!
会好起来的 回家吧
It'll get better.Go home.
你们这些留下来的明显不是得了伤风
Those of you who have stayedobviously do not have colds.
会有别的医生指派给你们
You will be assigned a doctor who is not me,
我不想再用棉签擦人的下体了
'cause I'm tired of wiping crotches.
House!
你得看病
You're doing this.
叫保安
Call security.
要不要我拿一针镇静剂?
Should I get a sedative?
不用 我很好 谢谢
No,I'm good.Thanks.
我头疼死了!
My head hurts!
需要一个医疗小组!
need a team here!
镇静剂来了
I have the sedative.
晚了点
A little late.
刚刚好
Just in time.
- 你刚才给他了什么,- 面部神经瘫痪
- What did you give him? - paralytic.
你干吗要那样做
why would you do that?
要让某人不要尖叫
Somebody hadto stop the screaming.
可是他还是会痛啊
Then he's still in pain.
对 但是安静的痛
Yeah,but quietly.
面部神经瘫痪会让他停止呼吸
The paralyticstopped his breathing.
如果脑部缺氧,他就得安静一辈子了
If he goes hypoxic,he's gonna be quiet forever.
要么让我继续用棉签去擦别人私处,或者让我想想这家伙的精神错乱和疼痛
So either I can continueto swab people's privates or I can figure outif this guy's delirium,pain,
疯狂的心率是有生命危险呢,还是只是一种古怪的人格
and insanely high heart rate are life-threatening or just a personality quirk.
我觉得第二种选择对我们三个都比较合适
I think the latter choiceis better for all three of us.
-=豪斯医生=-,S03E12 "One Day, One Room"
house Season 3 Episode 12
他打了镇静剂
he's sedated.
瘫痪消失以后 用了5cc的氟哌啶醇,(一种强安定药)才让他安静下来
It took 5ccs of haloperidol to get him down after the paralytic wore off.
右耳疼痛 精神错乱 头昏眼花
so,the pain in his right ear, psychotic behavior,and dizziness.
说吧!
Go!
护士说他经常敲自己的头
Nurses said he was smacking his head.
你怎么这么准确的知道是耳朵
How do you know it was specifically his ear?
因为他头晕
Because he was dizzy.
表示内耳出了问题
It means the problem was affecting his inner ear.
护士说他绕圆圈跑,并不表示他那时候头晕
Nurses said he was running in circles.Doesn't mean he was dizzy.
他并没有绕圆圈跑
He wasn't running in circles.
他是绕着方形跑
He was running in oblongs.
还是三岁小孩画的那种方形
Looked like a 3-year-old kid drew them.
听神经瘤大出血
Acoustic neuroma that started to hemorrhage.
解释疼痛 眩晕 所有症状
Explains the pain,vertigo,everything.
做个核磁共振
Get an mri.
还有什么可能
What else?
- 如果能解释所有症状,- 也可能解释不了所有的
- If it explains everything - might not explain everything.
好吧 如果他开始就有精神病呢
well,what if he was psychotic first,
然后自残 损害了耳部
then self-mutilated,damaged the ear.
很棒
Excellent.
需要全面的精神病学诊断
We need a complete psychiatric workup.
到你了
Your turn.
我本来要说的跟Foreman
Uh,I was gonna say what foreman.
好吧 那说点别的
well,say something else.
他 来了门诊
He.came to the clinic.
不错
Good.
很大可能是他先有了慢性病,特别是当有心率加快的现象出现
Decent chance he had a chronic illness first,especially given the rapid heart rate.
持续的耳部感染,增加了对内耳的压迫
Lingering ear infection.Pressure builds up in his inner ear
当他在门诊候诊的时候,通过中耳骨乳突爆发
and bursts through the mastoid bone while he's waiting in the clinic.
是啊
yes.
做脑部CT 血液培养,做生化电解分析
Get a head ct,draw blood cultures,run a chem panel,
还有一个全血计数
and get a complete blood count.
你们忙这些的时候,顺道往他耳朵里倒点酒精
Oh,while you're at it,pour some alcohol into his ear
然后把蟑螂拿出来
and take out the cockroach.
有个蟑螂在他耳朵里?
He has a cockroach in his ear?
他发疯之前一直在抓耳朵,所以我就偷看了一下
He was scratching that ear right before the event,so I took a peek.
我猜是因为它开始咬人了
My guess is it started biting.
他没有什么别的事?
Nothing else wrong with him?
好吧 这还不够么
Well,isn't that enough?
挺恶心的
It's pretty gross.
那么 我们干吗还要去作那么多检查
So.why are we doing the tests?
不做这些我就要接着去坐门诊
Well,it's either that or I have to keep doing clinic duty.
做检查 或者别让Cuddy看到就好了
Do the tests,or just stay out of cuddy's sight.
我倒不在乎你们选哪个
I don't really care which.
你怎么在这
Why are you here?
因为这不是医院
Because it's not a hospital.
这是慢跑公园啊
It's a jogging park.
你又不慢跑
You're not jogging.
你也慢跑不了
You can't jog.
我在看慢跑
I'm watching jogging.
我坐下 观看 然后想像
I sit,I watch,and I imagine.
那你都看什么
So what do you watch for?
那小伙子穿短裤跑
That guy's running in shorts.
他才没在跑步 他在钓马子
he's not running.He's trolling.
你挺擅长这个嘛
You're good at this.
你在这还要待多久
How long are you going to stay here?
这种地方的美好就在于,cuddy想不到到这里找我
The beauty of this place is it's the last placecuddy will look.
我能为您效劳吗
How can I help you?
医生们给了我这个
The doctors gave me this.
什么医生
What doctors?
别的医院的医生
At the other hospital.
上个月
last month.
你知道上面写了什么
Do you knowwhat this says?
知道
Yes.
病人右肺有一个6厘米的肿大,癌变 - 无法手术
The patienthas a 6-centimeter mass in the right lung--cancerous,inoperable.
你明白这意味着什么
Do you understandwhat this means?
我今晚在这里过夜可以么
Is it okayif I sleep here tonight?
外面很冷
It's cold outside.
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
我还以为house有个病人
I thought house had a case.
他没有
He doesn'T.
你给耳朵里有虫子的病人预定了CT
You ordered a ct on a patientwith a bug in his ear.
你怎么知道我在这
How'd you knowI was here?
我在门诊偶遇了cameron
Ran into cameronin the clinic.
"偶遇"?
"Ran into"?
你预约不必要的检查就是为了
You ordered pointless testsjust to--
如果你没有偶遇cameron,那就不会是没用的了
it wouldn'thave been pointless if you had"run into" cameron.
她受到惩罚了
She got punished.
她被一个垂死的病人粘住了
She's stuckwith another dying patient.
那是维柯丁?
Is that vicodin?
薄荷糖
Breath mint.
我以为你会亲我
Thought youwere gonna kiss me.
不是戒毒了吗
What happened to rehab?
我不去了
I got out.
- 那是诡计是吧,- 前戏够了吧
- it was a scam? - Enough foreplay.
你到底要不要亲我
Are you gonna kiss me or not?
你现在就回门诊去
You are going backto the clinic.
或者监狱
Or jaiL.
你作伪证把我弄出监狱,回头你怎么跟警察说
You perjured yourselfto keep me out of jail.How are you gonna tell--
我以为你会戒毒,所以才那样做
I only did that because I thought youwere getting clean.
所以要么去坐门诊要么就坐牢房
So it's do clinic dutyor go to jail?
对
Yes.
然后就会变成,"把你的文件整理好了要么坐牢"
And then it'll be, "finish your paper work "or go to jail,"
要么帮忙筹款要么坐牢
help with fundraisingor go to jail,
要么工作要么坐牢
do your job or go to jail.
我想我宁愿去坐牢
I think I'd rather go to jail.
你欠我的
You owe me.
真~漂亮
Be-yootiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
很干
It's dry.
管它呢
Who cares?
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
如果我的草坪能整理的有你那一半那么好
If my lawn were halfas well maintained as that,
那些鸽子怎么有胆量在上面拉屎
pigeons wouldn't have the nerveto poop on it.
修理边幅很重要
Good grooming is important.
有用吗?
Was that a shot?
人们会根据外表评价你这个人
People do judge youon your appearance.
我发现你的衬衣没熨过
When you entered I notedyour shirt hadn't been pressed,
很久没刮胡子
you hadn't shavedin quite some time.
我推断你是一个不关心细节的人
I extrapolated youwere a person for whom detail was not a major concern.
我担心你工作也一样马虎
I was worriedyou might apply that same standardin your work.
你在那用了剪脚指甲的剪刀么
Do you use toenail clippersup there?
那种更长 所有能够得着里面的毛
They're longer,so they allow me to better reachthe upper hairs.
我穿皱巴巴的衬衣,这个礼拜还忘记梳头发
I'm wearing a rumpled shirt and forgot to brush my hairthis week.
可你鼻子里长了脚癣
You've got athlete's footin your nose.
我现在准备好被人评价了
I'm ready to be judged.
好了
Okay.
哪个病人现在就闪人,我给他50刀
$50 to any patient who is willingto leave here right now.
House,
House
- 你不能,- 我的钱
- you can't - my money.
我不管 人总不能--
I don't care.People do not--
如果他们为了50块闪人,说明病的根本不重
if they'll leavefor 50 bucks, they're not all that sick.
或者说明他们穷而且敢玩命,所以医院门诊才存在
Or they're poorand desperate, which is why this placeis here.
如果他们真那么穷,他们肯定宁愿要那50块
If they're that poor, then they'd rather have50 bucks.
能给我钱么
Can I have the money?
看 印着姓名缩写呢
Look,it's monogrammed.
他不需要这钱 因此他没病
He doesn't need money,ergo he's not sick.
那血怎么回事
And the blood?
可能是任何别人的
Could be anybody'S.
这字母肯定是他的
The monogram's definitely his.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
你说什么 做什么,怎么威胁都没关系
it doesn't matter what you say,do,or threaten,
我总会找到出路的
I will find a way out.
怎么才能让你对门诊感兴趣
How can we make thismore interesting for you?
怎么才能把天空变绿
How can we makethe sky green?
怎么才能把高的变矮
How can we make the tall short?
你不能把无聊的事情变有趣
You cannot makethe uninteresting interesting.
你要是不碰病人就能诊断,每个病人我给你10块钱
I'll pay you $10 for every patient you diagnosewithout touching.
你碰了一个病人就要给我10块钱
You pay me $10 for every oneyou have to touch.
你要把这个变成我的游戏
You're making thisinto a game for me.
从这点上看我只能推断,这对你来说不是游戏
From which I can only conclude this isn't a game for you.
没错
No.
干吗 以为我看的病人足够多,就会变得仁慈?
Why?You think if I dealwith enough people I'll find some humanity?
没错
Yes.
我干哈要自己弄这个啊
Why do I ha--to do thi-- mysel--?
我腿坏了
I got a bum leg.
说,"ahh
Say,"ahh.
Ahh.
感觉很粗糙
It feels rough.
是啊 那可是皮疹
Yes,it's a rash.
我得需要比"粗糙."详细点
I'm gonna need morethan "rough."
就只是凹凸不平
It--it's just rough.
你就不能摸一下?
Can't you feel it?
可以 但是你会得到快感么?
I could,but then what satisfactionwould you get?
感觉到了
Got it.
开始计数
Start counting.
多少?
How many?
26.
20.
好吧
okay.
或者你数学太滥或者你两秒内挂掉
either you suck at math or you're gonna diein two seconds.
数学太滥
You suck amath.
断病
DiagnosiS.
开方
Prescription.
你欠我30
You owe me 30.
欠你10块
I owe you ten.
那个性病患者的检查结果出来了
Test results are backfor your std patients.
这个我不会算进去的
And I'm not paying youfor them.
你先前碰过的
You already touched them.
你多大了?
How old are you?
30.
你从没看过课后特别读物 恋爱时代?,(亦名道森的小溪，关于青春成长的剧集)
And you've never seenan afterschool special,dawson's creek?
你都30岁了还不懂得用套套?
How do you get to 30and not know about condoms?
哦 天哪 我染上了
Oh,god,I-I have an std.
没有 但是会有的
No,but you will.
每个来做性病测试的病人都有一点相同
Every patient who comesin here for an std test has one thing in common:
他们都是sws.
They had sws.
爱做也爱犯傻
sex whe stupid.
您贵庚?
How old are you?
60.
60?
撒谎
You're lying.
但是无关紧要
But that's not the point.
你从没看过恋爱时代?
You've neverseen dawson's creek?
你从不看课后特别读物?
And you've never seenan afterschool special?
你这么大了还不懂得用套套?
How do you live to your ageand not know about condoms?
我染上了么?
I have an std?
是的 实际上今天你是头一个
You're actuallythe first one today.
幸运日
Lucky day.
好吧 对你来说不是.
Well,not for you.
但是你应该为其他人感到高兴
But you oughta feel good for everyone else.
只是衣原体感染
It's chlamydia.
坏消息中最好的一种
As bad news goes,it's about the best.
哦 别伤心了
Oh,settle down.
能治好的
It's treatable.
真的能治愈的
It's actually curable.
你要做就是吞了这些药片
All you gotta dois take these pilllls--
别碰我!
don'touch me!
哦 上帝
Oh,god.
我需要人来替我
I need someoneto cover a patient.
House 你答应过的
House,you committed to--
她被强暴了
she was raped.
你觉得我是合适人选么?
You think I'm the right doctorfor her?
我们指定了另一个医生负责你的治疗
we've assigned another doctorto your care.
我不是有意冒犯House医生的
I didn't meanto upset dr.House.
他知道
He knows that.
这不是我们这么做的原因
That's not whywe're doing this.
我想要他来继续治疗我
I'd like to keepbeing treated by him.
- 为什么? - 做就是了
- Why? - Just do.
相信我 由专家来处理你的情况会更好
Well,trust me,it's betterif you deal with somebody who specializes in--
我很好
I'm fine.
你告诉House医生这事到现在还不到一星期
You told dr.Houseit's been less than a week.
除了他你没有告诉其他人
You haven't told anyoneother than him.
- 从情感上讲 你仍然-,- 你知道我现在的情况么?
- Emotionally,you're still - you knowwhat I'm dealing with?
你知道我所经历的么?
You knowwhat I'm going through?
不知道
No.
你觉得House医生知道?
You think dr.House does?
我不是建议让我们做你的主治医生
I'm not suggesting either oneof us be your doctor.
Stone医生是位心理医师
Dr.Stoneis a psychiatrist.
如果House医生太忙 我可以等
If dr.House is too busy,I could wait.
为什么你要我来?
Why do you want me?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不想给你治病
I don't want to treat you.
你这么说只是要让我去看心理医生
You're just saying that so I'll seethe psychiatrist.
是的 但不是"只是"
True,except for the word "just."
不想给你治病是要你去看心理医生
I'm saying I don't want see youso you'll see the psychiatrist
还因为我不想给你治病
and because I don't wantto treat you.
为什么你不再给我治病了?
Why don't you wantto treat me anymore?
我从没想过要给你治病
I never wanted to treat you.
你被强暴了
The factthat you were raped.
对我来说不感兴趣
holds no interest for me.
不是针对你
It's nothing personal.
没什么可治的
There's nothing to treat.
你的身体是健康的
You're physically healthy.
好吧
Okay.
但是我要你做我的主治医生
But I want youto be my doctor.
为什么?
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
好 你得有个理由吧
Well,you've gotta have a reason.
凡事皆有缘由
Everything has a reason.
我信任你
I trust you.
你看 这个理由不太高明
Now,you see,that's a bad reason.
看 我会对你满口胡话
See,I'll lie to you.
为了让你从这里出去我会口不择言
I'll tell you anything just to get you out of here.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我要和你说话
I want to talk to you.
听着 你被强暴了
Look.you were raped.
你对现实感到无力,想重新找回掌控一切的感觉
Now,all controlwas taken away from you, and you're trying to findthat control again.
你想要我是因为我不想要你
You want mebecause I don't want you.
我是在强暴你么?
I'm raping you?
以非伤害方式 更烦人--
In a very non-invasive,more annoying--
给我滚出这里!
get the hell out of here!
我会叫Stone来
I'll send in dr.Stone.
我没有同意这些用药
I didn't consentto all this medicine.
你曾流落街头
You've been outon the streets.
- 得不到治疗,- 我快要死了
- No treatment - I'm dying.
死亡是无可医治的
There's no treatment for dying.
我们可以让你好过一些
We can make you comfortable.
- 不想要,- 为什么?
- Don't wanna be. - Why not?
因为我把生活弄得乱七八糟
Because I screwed up my life.
所以你要自我惩罚?
So you wantto punish yourself for messing up your life?
拜托了
Please.
中止治疗
stop the treatment.
它会自行消失的
It'll go awayon it's own.
不会的 你能不能?
It's not.Can't you-
不能 会消失
Nope.It'll go away.
这样子已经一整天了
It's been all day.
你肯定有什么法子的--
There must be some treatmentyou can--
没有 会消失的
nope. It'll go away.
或者就这样子
Or it won't go away.
我看到过一个疗法
I read about a treatment.
还有医生因为这个得了奖,(搞笑诺贝尔医学奖：按摩肛门止打嗝)
Some doctorwon a prize for it.
我看过的
I read about it.
你不是打嗝吧 是不是?
You don't have the hiccups,do you?
记下来
Make a note.
骗药的
Drug-seeking behavior.
- 吗啡?,- 不是
- Morphine? - No.
后庭金手指
Anal digital stimulation.
Stone和她在里面多久了?
How long has stonebeen in with her?
你关心么?
Are you concerned?
你知道每天多少人被强暴?
You know how many peopleget raped every day?
所以这很寻常 就是说没意思?
So it's common,therefore boring?
如果我要关心地球上每个受苦受难的人
If I were to careabout every person suffering on the planet,
日子就没法过了
life would shut down.
那我们遇到的这些呢?
How about just the oneswe meet?
他们比别人更值得同情?
They deserve our sympathymore than the other people?
所你的解决之道就是谁都不鸟?
So your solution is not to givea damn about any of them?
你如何做到?
How do you do that?
你如何把这套理论付诸实践?
How do you take that theory and put it in practice?
你遇到了她
You met her
一小时前我付给这些人50块离开这里
I paid these people 50 bucks to leave here an hour ago.
是的 我们回来了
Yeah,we came back.
好吧 那么你欠我50块
Well,then,you owe me 50.
这孩子需要动手术
The kid needs surgery.
当时他可是行走自如
and he could walk way back then.
站起来 孩子
Stand up,kid.
他吞了一块磁铁
He swallowed a magnet.
我们得动手术刀了
We gotta cut it out.
你多大了?
How old are you?
8岁
8.
他吞下了吸在冰箱上的某物
And he swallowed somethingstuck to a fridge.
达尔文说他可以死了
Darwin says let him die.
已经过了胃了 它会自己排出去的
It's alreadybelow the stomach. It should passon its own.
强磁体
Strong magnet.
会干扰成像 我们没法确定--
It's messin'with the imaging. We have no way to--
你有x光电眼 House?
you got x-ray vision,house?
哦 你要给他开刀?
Oh,you gonna cut him open?
就在这里?
Right here?
已经到肠子里了
It's well into the intestines.
他没事的
He's fine.
还我的50块
I want my 50 back.
我要救护担架 快
need a crash cart,stat.
怎么了?
What happened?
吞药--benzos(治疗忧郁).
pills--benzos.
需要给她洗胃
We needto get her stomach pumped.
呼吸短促
Respiration's shallow.
你对她说了什么?
What did you say to her?
- 没有什么会让她-,- 心跳不正常
- Nothing that wouldmake her want to - heartbeat's irregular.
她对你说了什么?
What did she say to you?
没什么 我给了她几粒镇静药 转过身
Nothing.I gave her a coupleof sedatives,turned around,
她整瓶抓起
she grabbed the whole bottle.
你肯定说了什么
You must have said something.
我说了不少
I said plenty.
她什么都没说
She said nothing.
我和她在一起超过一小时
I was with herfor over an hour.
她一言未发
She didn't say one word.
你还会这么干么?
Are you gonna do that again?
你会好起来的 身体上
You're gonna be okay.Physically.
这是唯一能让你感兴趣的
Which is allthat interests you.
但是你来了
But you're here.
奉命行事
Under orders.
你为什么要告诉我?
Why would you tell me that?
因为我不喜欢伪善
Because idon't like hypocrisy.
但是铁石心肠对你来说没有问题?
But you don't have a problemwith cruelty?
这把我们又绕回来了
Which brings usback to.
为什么你想要我?
why do you want me?
我不知道
I don't know.
不能和我谈话就自杀
You tried to kill yourself, because you couldn'ttalk to me.
你肯定有原因
You must have a reason.
为什么总要有一个理由?
Why does there always have to be a reason?
我们就不能只是谈一谈?
Can't we just talk?
这里有电话
There's a phone.
和朋友谈 和家人谈
Talk to a friend,a family member.
报警
Call the police.
要不要说一下你怎么了么?
Do you want to talkabout what happened to you?
不要
No.
你要谈谈你的用药么?
Do you want to talkabout your std meds?
不要
No.
你看起来不像是真的要谈话
You don't really seemto want to talk.
不是的 我要
No,I do.
谈什么?
About what?
我不知道
I don't know.
什么都行
Anything.
谈天气也行?
The weather?
你被强奸了 却想和我谈天气?
You were raped,and you want to talkabout the weather?
对
Yeah.
我才不和你谈这个
I'm not gonna talk to youabout the weather.
还是您来吧…
You help her.
她要的是你
She wants you.
谁知道呢…
God knows why.
她根本不知道她想要什么
She doesn't knowwhat she wants.
她很清楚她需要你
She knows she wants you.
你是第一个知道这件事的人
You're the first personshe spoke to about this.
虽说这倒霉事是被我碰上的--
The fact that I was in the wrong placeat the wrong time
可毕竟我在这方面是个废人
should be trumped by the factthat I'm useless at this.
你行的
No,you're not.
别做白日梦了 这根本不可能的
you romantically wanting to believe that is nevergonna make it true.
我是站在你一边地
I'm agreeing with you.
她最不该找的就是你
You are the last person she should be talking to.
她想谈天气 那就谈呗
If she wants to talkabout the weather,talk about the weather.
她想让一切恢复正常
She wants normalcy.
她想感到这不是世界末日
She wants to feellike the world didn't end.
那行…
Right.
我就告诉她没了她地球照样转
I'll tell her that everythingwent on without her:
人类继续繁衍生息
Babies were born,people got married.
她被强奸的那天,也许对成千上万的其他人--
Thousands of people will remember the day
是最快乐的一天
she got raped as the happiest dayof their lives.
你不会真要这么说吧？
You might not wantto phrase it quite that way.
你得让她谈到底怎么出的事
You need to get herto talk about what happened.
不能这么干
no,he doesn'T.
假装一切没发生--
Pretending it didn't happen--
现在对她最好就是假装一切都没发生
Wrong.Pretending this didn't happen is the best thingshe could possibly do.
得让她正视这一切
She's gotta make this real.
你知道我们到底该正视什么吗?
You know what we should be trying to make real or process?
--生命中少数的几件好事,不是这种烂事儿
The few decent momentsin our lives,not the crap.
也许没错 可她不可能假装没有这件事
Maybe you're right,except there's no way she can pretendthis didn't happen.
除了正视之外 她别无选择
So she has no choicebut to process it.
跟我说说到底怎么出的事
You've got to tell mewhat happened.
你才不想听呢
You don't reallywant to hear.
- 我当然想听,- 骗人
- Sure i do. - You're lying.
没必要因为这个毁了一辈子
This doesn't haveto destroy your life.
我知道
I know.
这件事不是你造成的
It doesn't mean anythingabout you.
不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
我知道
I know.
你什么也没做错
You did nothing wrong.
只是被个混蛋伤害了而已
Some jerk hurt you.That's all.
我知道
I know.
你担心以后再不能信任男人
You're worried that youcan never trust men again.
没有
No.
统计上来说 难免会出这种事的
Statistically,there was always a chance this could happen.
即便真出事了 也改变不了什么
The fact that it did happen doesn't change anything.
世界已经够烂 明天并不会更糟
The world doesn'tsuck any more today than it did yesterday.
这些我都知道
I know all that.
你到底想让我跟你谈什么?
Well,what do you want meto tell you?
没什么
Nothing.
只是想聊聊
I just wanna talk.
聊没什么大不了的事
About nothing.
闲聊的话 没什么会改变的
If we talk about nothing,nothing will change.
- 不见得,- 怎么改变?
- It might. - How?
时间
Time.
时间能改变一切
Time changes everything.
人人都这么说
That's what people say.
其实不是这样的
It's not true.
行为才能带来改变
Doing things changes things.
什么也不做...
Not doing things...
只会让一切保持原样
leaves things exactlyas they were.
干嘛非要受这个罪呢?
Why do you have to suffer?
我答应过别人
I gave my word.
谁还让你答应这种事啊?
Who would make youpromise that?
我父亲
My father.
他说我会孤苦伶仃的死去
He said I would die aloneand miserable.
这不算承诺 即便是 他也死了
That's not a promise,and even if it was,he's dead.
就算他没死 他也不会在乎的
And even if he's not,he's not going to care.
你丈夫又是何苦呢?
Why did your husbandhave to suffer?
你怎么知道我丈夫?
How do you knowabout my husband?
我就是知道
Well,I just know.
就因为对你父亲的承诺,你就非得痛苦的死去?
You have to die in pain because of a promise you made to your father?
我说是的话 你肯定用这个证明我疯了
If I'd say yes,you'd use that as proofthat I'm insane.
逼我接受治疗
Force treatment on me.
护士告诉你我丈夫的事的?
Did the nurse tell youabout my husband?
不是
No.
- 护士?,- 是…
- Nurse? - Yes.
没事了
It's under control.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我就是想吓吓你
I was just tryingto freak you out.
为什么?
Why?
因为我得让你记住我
Because I need youto remember me.
我希望有人能记住我
I need somebodyto remember me.
上的什么大学?
Where'd you go to college?
西北大学
Northwestern.
- 你呢?,- 霍普金斯
- You? - Hopkins.
什么专业?
What was your major?
比较宗教学
Comparative religion.
为什么信任我?
Why do you trust me?
不知道
I don't know.
- 咱们能不能...,- 这根本不合道理!
- Can't we just... - that's not rational!
没什么是合理的
Nothing's rational.
一切都该是合乎道理的
Everything is rational.
我被强奸了
I was raped.
你觉得这怎么合理了?
Explain how thatmakes sense to you.
我们不过是一群占据大地的自私动物
We are selfish,base animals crawling across the earth.
但由于我们有智力,如果努力尝试
But because we've got brains,if we try real hard,
我们偶尔也会做出点不那么糟的事
we can occasionally aspire to something that is lessthan pure evil.
你身上发生过什么糟糕的事情吗?
Has anything terribleever happened to you?
你到底想让我说什么?
What do you want me to say?
是你提出要谈谈
You wanted this conversation.
说说心里的想法
You wanted to talk about something that matters.
说吧
Talk.
她还在等你回答?
She's waitingfor your answer?
她睡着了
She's asleep.
我给她用了镇静剂
I sedated her.
你为什么在乎和她的谈话?
Why do you carewhat you say to her?
因为我不知道如何回答那些问题
Because I don't know howto answer these questions.
问题很简单 你的生活是不是一团糟
It's a simple question:Has your life sucked?
跟她讲实话
Tell her the truth.
说你受了枪伤
Tell her you were shot.
她根本不在乎什么实话
She doesn't wantto hear the truth.
她内心在寻找  或是想要--
She's looking for something,looking to extrapolate some--
她在想和你建立沟通
she's looking to connectwith you.
这种事你最怕了
And that's what's scaring the hell out of you.
告诉她实情
Tell her the truth.
根本没什么实情
There is no truth.
我们这是角色扮演?
Are we role-playing?
我扮你吗?  我可不想扮你
Am I you?I don't want be you.
她既没询问检验结果
She's not askingfor test results.
也没问二加二等于几
She's not askingwhat 2 plus 2 equals.
而是在探寻我的生活经历
She's asking for my personal life experience
好照搬到其他人身上
so she can extrapolateto all humanity.
这哪是实话
That's not truth.
荒谬的理论
That's bad science.
这根本算不上科学理论
It's not science at all.
告诉她实话
Tell her the truth.
和她说你的生活很愉快
Tell her your lifehas been good.
从来没有过
It hasn't been.
总之就这么说
Tell her anyway.
她需要希望
She wants hope.
她想确定在她身上发生的事情是个特例
She wants to knowthat what happened to her wasn't the norm,
事情过了一切都会好的,或许他们能让她好起来
that things can be okay,which means maybe they canbe okay for her again.
告诉她你的生活简直一团糟
Tell her your life sucked.
我哪有
It didn'T.
就这么说
Tell her anyway.
让她感到不再孤独
She wants to knowshe's not alone.
她能挺过来
She wants to knowshe's gonna survive this,
其他经历过更惨痛事情的人最终都,能从阴影中走出来
that other people have beenthrough this and worse and come outthe other end.
她也能痊愈
She wants to knowshe's going to heal.
就像 .... 你也"痊愈"了
Act like...you're healed.
告诉她... 还是让她睡着好了
Tell her...keep her asleep.
多谢  你们都给我出了不少主意
Thanks.You've all been a huge help.
这种事情根本无法分辨答案的正确与否
There's no wrong answer,because there'sno right answer.
不对
Wrong.
我们还没找到正确的而已
We just don't knowwhat the right answer is.
醒醒
Wake up.
发生在你身上的事情还没那么糟,至少我认为
It's not as badas what happened to you,I don't think.
我不清楚究竟发生了什么
I don't knowwhat happened to you.
但是就你的反应来看
But given how lousyyou're responding,
我猜比起我祖母的虐待要严重的多
I assume it was worse than getting abusedby your grandmother.
她怎么对你了?
What did she do to you?
我父母经常外出,把我留给她照顾
My parents traveled a lot,and they'd leave mewith her.
她喜欢说一不二
She liked thingsthe way she liked them.
什么都要求纪律
And she believed in discipline.
她是对的 我想是的  因为
She was right,I suppose,because
她在身边时我从不犯错
I hardly ever screwed upwhen she was around.
怕被罚在院子里睡觉,或是洗冰水浴
Too scared of being forcedto sleep in the yard or take a bath in ice.
该你了
Your turn.
你父母 他们=,从没阻止她?
Your parents,they--they never stopped her?
我从未告诉他们
I never told them.
为什么?
Why not?
理由很简单 我怕他们不信我
Usual reasons: I was afraidthey wouldn't believe me,
怕他们以为是我做错事
and I was afraid they'd thinkI'd done something wrong.
我说了  该你敞开心扉了
I opened up to you,you open up to me.
- 你怎么称呼她?,- Oma
- What did you call her? - Oma.
事情发生后你一直这么称呼她?
And you kept calling her thatafter this?
荷兰语的祖母
Dutch for "grandmother.
她还是我祖母 还是个荷兰人
" She was still my grandmother,and she was still dutch.
你说的话里有真的部分吗?
Is any partof that story true?
全是真的
All of it.
你不应该还叫她Oma
You wouldn't keepcalling her oma.
尤其是发生了这种事情
Something would have to change.
- 你不了解我,- 你不会叫她Oma
- You don't know me. - You wouldn't keepcalling her oma.
你反应过度了
Look,you're overreacting.
不要敷衍我
Do not dismiss me.
我没有
I'm not dismissing you.
我的意思是你现在不太理智
I'm just sayingyou're not acting rationally.
我生气是因为你说谎
I'm angry because youare lying to me.
不是  你--
No.You are--
那我应该怎么做?
What can I do?
怎么做你才不会编故事敷衍
What the hell can I dothat you're not gonna dismiss
一个被强暴的女孩
as just beingbecause I was raped?
什么都不必做
Nothing.
你的故事  ...到底是不是真的?
Your story...is it true?
有些人的是真的
True for somebody.
但不是你身上
But not for you.
有些事情发生了
These things happen.
在某些人身上发生
It happened to somebody.
在不在我身上有什么关系?
What do you careif it happened to me?
因为屋子里只有你
They're notin this room.
不! 他们就在那儿 医生 律师...,邮递员
No!They're out there:Doctors,lawyers...postal workers.
有人一切美满
Some of them doing great.
有人生活潦倒
Some of them doing lousy.
难道你要根据同屋的人,得出今后的一生?
Are you gonnabase your whole life on who you got stuckin a room with?
我要根据他来决定这一刻
I'm gonna base this moment on who I'm stuckin a room with.
这就是生活
That's what life is.
一间间屋子
It's a series of rooms.
每个曾经同屋的人,构筑了你的生活
And who we get stuckin those rooms with adds upto what are lives are.
House.
House
你得帮我一把
You've gotto get me out of this.
没病可看
There's nothing to diagnose.
- 没...,- 你只查了性病?
- There's nothing... - You only tested herfor stds?
我看了七个傻子,忘穿小夜衣
I had seven moronswho forgot their raincoats.
他们都怀疑得性病,所以没去浪费实验室的时间 怎么了
It's all they asked for,so I didn't wastethe lab's time.Why?
我去了
I wasted their time.
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
明白吗?
Do you understand?
还好吗?
Are you okay?
我知道你很糟 我是说 比起五分钟前
I mean,I know you're not okay,but are you moreor
多少是不是感觉更糟?
less not okay than you werefive minutes ago?
差不多
About the same.
很好
Good.
人流会不太舒服
The termination procedureisn't pleasant.
我没想做人流
I don't want to terminate.
你想要这孩子?
You want to keep the baby?
堕胎意味着谋杀
Abortion is murder.
对 是条命 可是...
True.It's a life,and...
你得结束他
you should end it.
生命都是神圣的
Every life is sacred.
晕 好好谈谈 别给我上课
Come on.Talk to me.Don't quote me bumper stickers.
- 我说得对,- 这有什么意义
- It's true. - It's meaningless.
意义在于 上帝眷顾一切生命
It means every lifematters to god.
没眷顾我 也没眷顾你
Not to me,not to you.
从自然灾害的数量来看,上帝不在乎人类
Judging by the numberof natural disasters,not to god either.
你只是在诡辩
You're just being argumentative.
是! 我是喜欢诡辩
Yeah!I do do that.
那希特勒怎样?
What about hitler?
他的命在上帝面前也是神圣的?
Was his life sacred to god?
这孩子的父亲 他的命,在你看来也是神圣的?
Father of your child,is his life sacred to you?
我孩子不是希特勒
My child isn't hitler.
生命要么都很神圣 那么--
Either every life is sacred,or it--
住口! 我不想聊哲学
Stop it!I don't wanna chatabout philosophy.
你的哲学要你留下强奸犯的孩子
You're not killingyour rape baby because of a philosophy.
这是谋杀 我反对 你支持?
It's murder.I'm against it.You for it?
不是说所有的
Not as a general rule.
没出生的孩子就可以?
Just for unborn children?
对
Yes.
例外的关键在于界限
The problemwith exceptions to rules is the line-drawing.
也许那个强奸犯该死
It might make sensefor us to kill the ass that did this to you.
但是 如何界定?
I mean,wheredo we draw the line?
哪些混蛋要死 哪些要留下,叫他们继续做混蛋?
Which asses do we get to kill,and which asses getto keep on being asses?
关于堕胎的争论有一点便利之处
The nice thingabout the abortion debate is
尽管三期的划分有得争论 但终究
that we can quibbleover trimesters,but ultimately,
有一条清晰的界限: 出生
there's a nice,clean line: Birth.
道德上 出生与否并无分别,操作起来就很大差别
Morally thereisn't a lot of difference.Practically,huge.
你喜欢这类话题
You're enjoyingthis conversation.
我擅长这类话题
This is the typeof conversation I do well.
不过另一类...
But the other type...
个人问题?
the personal stuff?
无从回答
There are no answers.
既然没法回答 谈它干嘛?
If there are no answers,why talk about it?
你很健康
You're healthy.
不该在这儿
You shouldn't here.
我不想离开
I don't want to go.
好 我不让你出院
Fine.I won't discharge you.
想散散步吗?
You wanna go for a walk?
旅途到了尽头
This is the lastof my journey.
这痛苦不是你该承受的
You don't deserve pain.
- 你只是失去了理智,- 不 不
- You're just an insane old man. - No,no.
我不会看着你受罪
I'm not gonna watch you suffer.
我要你记住我
I need you to remember me.
我会记住你的!
I'll remember you!
凭什么?
Why?
因为你是好人
Because you're a nice man.
你不明白
You don'know that.
你根本不了解我
You don't knowanything about me.
不管你是好是坏
Either you are a nice manor you're an ass.
你一定做过某些事,让别人能记住
Either way,you did somethingto somebody that they're gonna remember.
我没有家
I have no family.
没有朋友
I have no friends.
甚至没有像样的工作
I didn't even havea real job.
要是平平静静的死了 那我不过是,又一位普通的病人
If I die in peace,then I'm just another patient.
- 但如果我痛苦的死去--,- 会非常恐怖的
- But if I die suffering-- - it'll be horrible.
对你 对我 都别这样
Don't do thatto either of us.
不 我只是需要知道有些事因我而不同
No,I just need to die knowing that somethingis different because I was here.
噢... 噢 不
Oh...Oh,no.
生活还要继续
Life goes on.
我们到这儿来 就为这个?
Is that the reasonwhy we're out here?
嗯 为什么来这儿?
You know why I come here?
我坐在这儿 观察着 想象着
I sit,I watch,I imagine.
听上去不错
Sounds nicE.
想象他们中有人会断腿
I imagine that one of themwill break a leg.
仅仅一步之失 接着人行道上,传来啪的一声
Just one false step,one crackin the sidewalk.
你没有
You don't really.
我是个恶人
I'm evil.
恶人不会承认这点
Evil people don't saythey're evil.
听上去是个逻辑漏洞
That soundslike an easy loophole.
人们可以做好事
People can do good things.
但要是本性就不好
But if their instinctsare not good,
那只能说不存在上帝,或者他残酷到超乎想象
either god doesn't exist or he's unimaginably cruel.
我不信
I don't believe that.
那你信什么?
So what do you believe?
你觉得为什么会这样?
Why do you thinkthis happened?
我不想谈这个
I don't wantto talk about it.
一样
Me neither.
糟透了
Too bad.
我想这没什么原因
You know,I don't thinkthere was a reason.
啊 哈 那么存在上帝 他要你被强奸
Uh-huh,so god does exist,lets you get raped,
还要你毫无由头的留下强奸犯的孩子
and needs youto keep your rape baby for no reason.
好吧 或许他在考验我
Well,maybe hewas challenging me.
他伤害你 因为想帮你
He hurts you to help you.
这样的解释好过上帝讨厌你
I guess it's better than because he hates you.
你想要我相信没有上帝
You're trying to convince me there's no god.
你为什么非说这种话?
Why would you even saysomething like that?
因为你会毁了你的生活
Because you'rethrowing your life away.
我在按信仰办事
I'm doing what I believe.
你的信仰毫无道理
What you believedoesn't make sense.
这样帮不了我
This is not helping me.
那么我帮不了你
Then I can't help you.
如果你相信永恒 那还谈什么生命
If you believe in eternity,then life is irrelevant.
在宇宙面前 像一只小虫般微不足道
The same as a bugis irrelevant in comparisonto the universe.
如果你不相信永恒,那你这一世有什么意义
If you don't believein eternity,then what you do hereis irrelevant.
意义在于你如何过这一世
Your actions hereare all that matters.
有什么意义!
Then nothing matters.
既然没有终极后果
There's noultimate consequences.
我没法这样过
I couldn't livelike that.
所以你要让自己相信,犯事那家伙会遭天谴
So you need to think that the guy,who did this to you is gonna be punished.
我需要知道生而有意
I need to know that it all means something.
我需要安慰
I need that comfort.
是啊 舒服了吗?
Yeah.Are you feeling comfortable?
现在舒服了 心里暖暖的?
You feeling good right now,feel warm inside?
我被强奸了
I was raped.
你的说辞呢?
What's your excuse?
你觉得犯事那家伙的日子会难过吗?
Do you think the guywho did this to me feels bad?
对你有帮助吗?
That'd help you?
会让你感觉好些吗?
It'll make youfeel better?
你干嘛老这样...
Why do you always do that...
总是问我为什么这么问,而不去回答我的问题?
ask why I'm asking questions instead of just answering the question?
我对答案不感兴趣
Because the answerdoesn't interest me.
我不在乎他的感受
I don't carewhat he's feeling.
我关心你的感觉
I'm interestedin what you're feeling.
是吗?
You are?
我跟你困在一间房里 是吧?
I'm trapped in the roomwith you,right?
为什么选了我?
Why did you choose me?
你身上有些东西
There's somethingabout you.
告诉我你也受过伤
It's like you're hurt too.
是真的
It was truE.
什么是真的?
What was?
那事是真的 虽然不是我祖母
It wasn't my grandmother,but it was true.
是谁?
Who was it?
我爸爸
It was my dad.
现在我愿意告诉你发生了什么
I'd like to tell youwhat happened to me now.
我愿意听
I'd like to hear it.
是在我朋友的生日晚会上...
It was my friends' birthday party
她做了人流
she terminated.
出院了
She's been discharged.
会没事的
She's gonna be okaY.
能这么简单就好了
Yeah.It's that simple.
她说了经过
She's talkingabout what happened.
很难得 做得好
That's huge.You did good.
大家会说如果想帮她
And everyone'll tell you that's whatwe gotta
就得让她说出来 对吧?
make her do if we're gonna help her,right?
其实我们没帮到她
Except we can'T.
我们从她嘴里套出故事 告诉大家,以为这样会帮她康复
We drag out her story,tell each other that it'll help her heal,
然后自己感觉良好
and feel real goodabout ourselves.
或许我们做到的,只是让一个女孩哭
But maybe all we've doneis make a girl cry.
那你干嘛--
Then why did you--
因为我不知道
Because I don't know.
你要跟进她的病例?
you gonna follow upwith her?
一天一间屋
One day.One room.